<Defs>
    <HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef Abstract="true" Name="UpdateFeatureBase">
        <modNameReadable>Pawnmorpher</modNameReadable>
        <modIdentifier>Pawnmorpher</modIdentifier>
        <linkUrl>https://discord.gg/BK2S5tQ</linkUrl>
    </HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef>
    <HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef ParentName="UpdateFeatureBase">
        <defName>Pawnmorpher_1_6_0</defName>
        <assemblyVersion>1.6.0</assemblyVersion>
        <content>|img:UI/SapientUpdate|Pawnmorpher has a Discord server! Click 'Link' at the top to join. Get an early look at new features only from here!|&lt;b&gt;WHAT'S NEW?&lt;/b&gt;|- Revamped &lt;b&gt;Sapient Animal System&lt;/b&gt;. Former humans now have intelligence ranging from feral to sapient. Anything but feral is draftable, has mood and has needs. Keep sapient animals happy to prevent them from having mental breaks which will push them towards feral. Sapient animals can do work, interact with pawns, play chess and the like. Mental breaks (and feral pills) will reduce their sapience -- so keep them happy!|- Added &lt;b&gt;Free Morph Enclaves&lt;/b&gt;, a neutral faction populated entirely by morphs.|- Added &lt;b&gt;7 new aspects&lt;/b&gt; which can be encountered randomly from mutations. Discover all their wondrous effects!|- Revamped &lt;b&gt;mutagenic weapons&lt;/b&gt;. We added some melee weapons, a rocket launcher, as well as the Mutarifle which does a small amount of damage but inflicts mutagenic buildup. Mutagenic grenades and mortar shells will now add mutagenic buildup, and on a direct hit might sometimes instantly transform a victim.|- Added &lt;b&gt;morphsilk&lt;/b&gt;, a fabric that's better than regular cloth for clothing, but also increases the rate at which pawns gain mutations if worn. Does not give mutations by itself.|- Added extra stages for some parts that need them, paws will start at 'clawed' for hands etc.|- Added 'Dry' pills so pawns won't produce resources (so Etherbond/broken can be avoided)|- Added 'X-Asepct' pills to remove Etherbond/Broken and any other aspects a pawn may have -- note that this also removes any production boosts.|- Added Sheepmorphs if you have the Livestock module of Vanilla Animals Extended. Additional morphs will be rolled out.|- Changed resurrector made at the drug lab to a 'reincarnation' serum.|- Added Chaobulbs, a plant which can be found growing next to mutanite, or around crashed mutagenic ship parts. Allows for tribal acquisition of mutations, and can be refined into slurry.|- Added the Chaoboar. If sapient, it can do useful types of work.|+ Other various tweaks and bug fixes.|Once again, thanks to everyone who's using Pawnmorpher! Come and join us on the Discord server and show us what you got!
        </content>
    </HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef>
    <HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef ParentName="UpdateFeatureBase">
        <defName>Pawnmorpher_1_5_0</defName>
        <assemblyVersion>1.5.0</assemblyVersion>
        <content>|img:UI/AspectUpdate|Pawnmorpher now has a Discord server! Click 'Link' at the top to join.|&lt;b&gt;WHAT'S NEW?&lt;/b&gt;| - Added &lt;b&gt;iTab&lt;/b&gt; for mutations, which tracks morph influences, production and 'aspects'. Shows up when a pawn gains a mutation.| - Added &lt;b&gt;log entries&lt;/b&gt; for mutations, viewable from the mutation tab.| - Added &lt;b&gt;aspects system&lt;/b&gt;, a mix between hediffs and traits so we don't clutter the health tab. Viewable from the tab.| - Added a &lt;b&gt;new trait&lt;/b&gt; called 'mutation affinity'. Like transhumanist, but for mutations. Also, Body Purists hate being or seeing mutants now.| - Factions &lt;b&gt;will care&lt;/b&gt; if you mutate their people!| - Fur/feather/hide mutations now spread to other parts. |Mech healer serum now also mutates parts it heals.|+ Other various tweaks and bug fixes.|Thank you all for playing and enjoying Pawnmorpher! We'd love to see your unethical madness over on our Discord. :)
        </content>
    </HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef>
</Defs>