<ModMetaData>
	<name>Pawnmorpher</name>
	<author>Mic</author>
	<supportedVersions>
		<li>1.0</li>
		<li>1.1</li>
	</supportedVersions>
	<description>Too many prisoners and not enough animals? We can change that. And maybe you at the same time.

  &lt;size=24&gt;Features&lt;/size&gt;

- Buy, find or create a range of mutagens to augment your pawns or prisoners, with an expanding array of animal-themed mutations! There is often a high chance that the affected pawn will fully transform into an animal, so mind that.

- Boost existing mutations with pills that improve their efficiency. Can that pawn lay eggs any faster? Sure they can!

- Revert transformed animals to their former human selves, provided they haven't spent too long as one.

- Stabilisers cancel out ongoing mutations, and prevents getting new ones, just like penoxycline. For the cautious.

- Fabricate guns to mutate raiders at a distance, but be warned that they may not always take it so well.

- New events: The mutagenic ship chunk, mutonite meteor and diseases such as cowflu might test your colonist's resolve! (Toggleable in mod settings)

- Chimera: There are three types of animal that can be attained by some special means or encountered in the wild.

  &lt;size=24&gt;Dependencies&lt;/size&gt;

  Requires Humanoid Alien Framework.

  &lt;size=24&gt;Full Release&lt;/size&gt;

You heard that right. This version is an improvement over Pawnmorpher Beta with a tonne of new features, visuals for mutations and some intricate little systems nobody will notice. There are more animal morphs, special chimeras and all manner of QOL addons.

This mod does require Humanoid Alien Framework to function, but also ships with out-of-the-box support for Giddy Up! Battle Mounts saddles (for the new chimeras).

Pawns who have been turned into animals can be reverted back to human with the right serum -- and they may have different outlooks on their time on all fours.

There's a new trader type, which buys prisoners and sells animals (as well as a stock of mutagens)...I'll leave you to connect the dots there.

Overall, this mod is just...better in every way to the original. Even so, there may be more to come.

  &lt;size=24&gt;Issues&lt;/size&gt;

Currently, only some small graphics issues with mutation offsets. Please report any you find, and any other bugs.

  &lt;size=24&gt;Integrations&lt;/size&gt;

- Giddy Up! | Perfectly compatible. Chaomorphs can be ridden, and if you're using Battle Mounts, they have saddles too.

- Horses (1.0) | Perfectly compatible. Patched in so pawns can turn into horses, with special injector as well.

- A Dog Said... | Perfectly compatible. Chaomorphs can have bionics now!

  &lt;size=24&gt;Friends&lt;/size&gt;

Massive, incredible thanks to Rocka, for doing basically all the textures. This version would not have happened without you.

Thanks to Menhi, Erdelf, and...many, many others who put up with me and my stupid questions on the RimWorld Discord.

  &lt;size=24&gt;Future Plans&lt;/size&gt;

With all core content out of the way, I can focus on more additions! More chaomorphs! More weapons! More end animals!

Feel free to suggest the next to be added, or if there are other QOL things you can think of.

	</description>
	<packageId>tachyonite.pawnmorpher</packageId>
	<modDependencies>
		<li>
			<packageId>erdelf.HumanoidAlienRaces</packageId>
			<displayName>Humanoid Alien Races 2.0</displayName>
			<steamWorkshopUrl>https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=839005762</steamWorkshopUrl>
		</li>
	</modDependencies>
	<loadBefore>
	</loadBefore>
	<loadAfter>
		<li>erdelf.HumanoidAlienRaces</li>
	</loadAfter>
</ModMetaData>
