<Defs>
    Aspects are a hybrid of Hediffs and Traits. Like traits they affect the whole pawn, not a single body part, but like Hediffs they can be added 
and removed 
    <Pawnmorph.AspectDef>
        the below field is used to set the aspect to a custom type, similar to hediffClass on HediffDefs , if ommitied the below is used 
        <aspectType>Pawnmorph.Aspect</aspectType>
        
        this label is used to set the color of the aspects label when displayed in the mutation tab 
        <labelColor>(1,1,1,1)</labelColor>
        
        this field is used to indicate whether this aspect should be removed by reverters or not, the default is true 
        <removedByReverter>true</removedByReverter>
        
        this is used to controll the sorting of aspects in the mutation tab, lower priorities are listed first. If two aspects have the same 
    priority then they are sorted alphabetically based on their label 
        <priority>1</priority>

        this field is used to indicate if this aspect should be transfered to the transformed pawn, if the pawn this aspect was first attached to transforms into an 
    animal 
        <transferToAnimal>false</transferToAnimal>

        this field is a list of thoughts that are blocked by this aspect 
        <nullifiedThoughts>
            <li>ThoughtDef</li>
        </nullifiedThoughts>

        this is a list of aspects that conflict with this aspect. If the pawn has one of the aspects listed below this aspect cannot be given to that pawn 
        <conflictingAspects>
            <li>AspectDef</li>
        </conflictingAspects>

        this lists traits that the pawn must have to be given this aspect 
        <requiredTraits>
            <li>TraitDef</li>
        </requiredTraits>

        this lists traits the pawn must not have to be given this aspect 
        <conflictingTraits>
            <li>TraitDef</li>
        </conflictingTraits>

        this is the list of stages this aspect has, there always must be at least one stage in an aspect or an error will be thrown during startup 
        <stages>
            <li>
                this is an optional field that if set will override the aspectDefs default label 
                <label></label>

                this is an optional field that if set will prefix the aspects label with whatevers set below in brackets  
                <modifier></modifier>

                optional field that if set will override an aspects default description 
                <description></description>

                optional field that if set will override an aspects default label color 
                <labelColor></labelColor>

                if true, marks the aspect at this stage as a negitive aspect
                <isBad></isBad>

                optional field that if set will be displayed as a message when a pawn is given this aspect. the message will be adjusted for the pawn that is given 
            the aspect, so use PAWN_nameDef etc. in the text 
                <messageText></messageText>

                optional messageDef that will be used to controll the type of message displayed when a pawn is given this aspect. if not set NeurtralEvent will be used 
                <messageDef></messageDef>

                this field is a list of thoughts that are blocked by this aspect 
                <nullifiedThoughts>
                    <li>ThoughtDef</li>
                </nullifiedThoughts>

                this field is a list of PawnCapacityModifiers, just like you find in an  HediffStage 
                <capMods></capMods>

                this field is a list of SkillModifiers 
                <skillMods>
                    <li>
                        the skillDef this modifier affects, this must be set 
                        <skillDef>SkillDef</skillDef>
                        
                        the amount of xp added when the pawn gains this aspect 
                        <addedXp></addedXp>

                        an offset to the pawns passion applied when the pawn is given this aspect 
                        <passionOffset>1</passionOffset>
                    </li>
                </skillMods>


                list of stat offsets like you would find in a HediffStage 
                <statOffsets></statOffsets>

                a list of production boosts applied to the pawn 
                <productionBoosts>
                    <li>
                        optional filter that restricts what kind of hediffs this production boost affects 
                        <hediffFilter>
                            if this filter uses a black list or white list. the default is a black list 
                            <isBlackList>true</isBlackList>
                            a list of hediffs that set what hediffs get filtered 
                            <filterList>
                              <li>HediffDef</li>  
                            </filterList>
                        </hediffFilter>

                        the offset to the severity to all productive mutations that pass the filter  
                        <productionBoost></productionBoost>
                    </li>
                </productionBoosts>
            </li>
        </stages>
    </Pawnmorph.AspectDef>
</Defs>